我是蘭姆
This is Lamb.
如果我沒接電話 那是因為我不想跟你說話
If I didn't answer, it's because I don't want to speak to you.
喂 騙到你了吧 我是馬庫斯·朗裏奇 請留言
Hello. Got you, didn't I? It's Marcus Longridge. Leave a message.
給 慢用 謝謝
Here you go. Enjoy. Cheers.
我是瑞弗 請留言
This is River. Leave a message.
喂
Hello?
終於有人接電話了
Finally. Someone picked up.
你在哪
Where are you?
關你屁事
None of your business.
好吧 你應該來雞多多快餐的
Yeah, well, you're supposed to be at the Chickado.
為什麼
Why?
我們的聖誕派對啊
Our Christmas party.
我們沒有聖誕派對
We don't have a Christmas party.
如果有 那也是在聖誕節前開 而且不會在雞多多快餐
And if we did, we'd have it before Christmas and not at a Chickado.
好吧 也許你沒被邀請
Yeah. Well, maybe you're not invited.
也許蘭姆只跟精英說了
Maybe Lamb only told the elites.
可蘭姆跟你說了 對吧
Lamb told you about it though, didn't he?
我問他聖誕派對在哪開 他就把細節告訴我了
I asked him where the Christmas party was, and he gave me the details.
是啊
Right.
你想想看是怎麼回事吧
See if you can work out what happened.
好吧 也得是局內人才會被耍 所以
Yeah, well, you gotta be in the game to get played, so...
喂
Hello?
在韋斯特艾克斯購物中心
At Westacres shopping center.
確認 是汽車炸彈
Confirmed there's a car bomb.
(韋斯特艾克斯)
局長來了
First Desk approaching.
我是克勞德·惠蘭局長
Claude Whelan, First Desk.
你是 特工辛格
And you are? Agent Singh.
好 長官
Right. Ma'am.
這種事 沒法形容
I mean, something like this, there are-There are no words.
真是
It's just...
我們確認了是汽車炸彈
We're confirmed it's a car bomb?
是 長官 監控拍到了
Yes, ma'am. We have it on CCTV.
司機在車上 所以是自殺式襲擊
Driver was in the car, so it was a suicide attack.
襲擊購物中心 老天啊
On a shopping center. My God.
汽車駛過步行區
Car drives up through the pedestrianized area,
人群四散
people scatter,
他直接駛進入口 然後引爆
he drives straight into the entrance and detonates.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
有那輛車的信息嗎
What do we know about the car?
是以羅伯特·溫特斯的名字租的 28歲的自由職業IT顧問
Hired under the name Robert Winters, 28-year-old freelance IT consultant,
但從他的背景中看不出他這麼幹的原因
but nothing in his background to indicate why he did this.
用監控查他的行蹤 我們必須知道他從哪來的
Track his journey on CCTV. We need to know where he came from.
我們查了他給租車公司的地址 位於萊斯特
We checked the address in Leicester he gave to the hire-car company.
那裏已經很多年沒人住了
Nobody's been there in years.
鄰居們從沒見過或聽說過溫特斯
Neighbors have never seen nor heard of Winters.
天啊
Jesus.
也許他是個幽靈人
So maybe he's a ghost.
有可能 這也許是一次性襲擊事件
Could be this is a one-off.
也可能是某件事的開端
Or the start of something.
我們訪問了一些倫敦人
And from talking to people in London, it seems
似乎整個社區依然很焦慮
that a sense of anxiety remains across the community.
在最新一次行動裏 武裝警察進駐部分地鐵列車
In the latest move, armed police have been placed on some trains,
雖然這更像是增加自信的舉措
although this feels more of a confidence-boosting measure
而不是針對某一特定威脅的應對
than a response to a specific threat.
你真的認為他從屬於一個組織嗎
Do you really think he is part of a network?
我想下一次襲擊間隔越久
I guess the longer it goes without another attack,
他越可能是獨狼吧
the more likely he's just a lone wolf.
我討厭「獨狼」這個詞 讓他顯得很神秘
I hate the term "lone wolf." Makes him sound edgy.
他只是個殺人的混蛋
He's just a murderous prick.
對 我們重新敬酒
Right. We'll do that again.
我們剛剛向一個 殺人的混蛋敬酒 說點別的
We just toasted a murderous prick. Say something else.
祝我們明年這個時候不在斯勞部門了
To not being in Slough House this time next year.
好 不太可能
Yeah. That's unlikely.
除非我們辭職
Unless we just quit.
你其實不想辭職
You don't actually wanna do that,
對吧
do you?
其實吧 我一直想辭職 真的
Well, I'm always thinking about it. Yeah.
太好了
Great.
總之呢 有件事
Anyway, yeah, there's just been something
我一直想跟你說 就是
that I've wanted to share with you for a while, and, you know,
我想在辦公室之外說 好吧
I wanted to do it outside of the office... Okay.
我覺得我可以跟你說
...and I've felt like I could share that with you
因為我們 我覺得我們的關係更親近了
'cause we've-I think we've gotten closer.
是的 所以
Uh-huh. And...
我不想越界什麼的
I don't want to overstep the mark or anything,
如果你想保持我們之間的工作關係 我完全理解
and I get it if you want to keep it to work when it comes to us.
瑞弗 抱歉 就是
Oh, River. I'm sorry. Just--
我是喜歡你 但 但我爺爺
I do like you, but-But my grandfather--
什麼 不 你爺爺 說吧
What? No, your grandfather. Yeah.
是 你剛才說什麼
Yeah, what did you just say?
我沒 沒什麼 你繼續 你以為我要說什麼
I didn't-No. Go on. Carry on. What did you think I was gonna say?
你以為我要約你出去 才不是
Did you think I was gonna ask you out? No, I didn't.
你就是 不是 好吧 我是
Yes, you did. Yeah, you did. I didn't. Okay, I did.
但那是因為你要求午餐時出來喝酒
But that's because you asked for a drink at lunchtime
想跟我說一件事
'cause you wanted to talk to me about something,
然後你囉哩囉嗦說什麼感覺
and then you started whanging on about how close
我們更親近了 是 囉哩囉嗦
you felt to me and then-Yeah. Whanging on?
是真的 我感覺跟你更親近了 現在能說你爺爺的事了嗎
Well, I do. I feel closer to you. Can we go on to your grandfather now?
好
Okay.
我覺得他越來越 越來越什麼
I think he's going-Going where?
就是
Like...
他總是犯糊塗
He's just confused all the time.
什麼都記不住
Forgets everything.
上了年紀的人不都是這樣嗎
Isn't that just part of aging?
他得有80多歲了吧 不
He's like, what, 80-something? No, no.
他認為自己被「白鼬」監視
He thinks he's being watched by stoats.
白鼬是什麼
What are stoats?
他那一代人對監視特工的叫法
It's what his generation call watchers.
他現在睡覺時床頭放一支槍
He's sleeping with a gun by the bed.
就是
Like...
你覺得他是不是應該進敬老院
Do you think that maybe he should be in a home?
是 我覺得應該 但怎麼跟他說啊
Yeah. Yeah, I do. But do you wanna tell him that?
上次我見他 他基本上頭十分鐘
You know, the last time I saw him, he genuinely didn't know who I was
根本認不出我
for, like, the first ten minutes.
完全不認識
No idea.
不停地跟我說他孫子瑞弗的事 我不能
He kept telling me about his grandson River. I can't--
看他這樣我太難受了
It's horrible to see it.
確實不幸
Well, tough shit.
什麼 是他把你帶大的
What? He is the one that raised you.
沒人管你時 是他照顧你
He is the one that looked after you when no one else did.
現在輪到你照顧他了
So now it's your turn.
你必須去看看他 今晚就去
You need to go and see him. Tonight.
不是 我知道 對 我知道
No, I know, I know. Yeah, I know. Yeah.
我只是需要聽你對我說這些話
I just needed you to tell me that.
我知道你在 出來吧 讓我看看你 來啊
I know you're there. Come on. Let me see you. Come on.
出來啊
Come on!
出來吧 我知道你在 來啊
Come on. I know you're there. Come on.
讓我看看你
Let me see you.
出來吧
Come on!
瑞弗
Oh, River.
能讓我進去嗎 我渾身濕透了
Can you let me in? I'm getting soaked.
當然
Yes, of course.
進來
Come in.
你怎麼不打電話提前說一聲 還是說你打了
Why didn't you call? Or maybe you did.
我打了 但你沒接 我要用下廁所
I did call you, but you didn't answer. I'm just gonna run up to the loo.
交通糟透了 這樣吧 我既然都上樓了 給你放一缸洗澡水如何
Traffic was awful. And I'll tell you what, shall I run you a bath while I'm up there?
看起來你也淋雨了
Looks like you got caught in the rain too.
太難受了
It's just awful.
就快好了 爺
Almost ready, Gramps.
你不是我孫子
You're not my grandson.
別開槍 是我 瑞弗啊
Whoa. It's me. It's River.
拜託 請把槍放下好嗎
C-Please. Can you put the gun down please?
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 我幹了些什麼
Oh, my God. What have I done?
(根據米克·赫倫的著作《驚魂街》改編)
該死
Fuck.
我是蘭姆
Lamb.
見鬼
Fuck.
我進一步瞭解情況後打給你
I'll call you when I've got more info.
他們在勘查現場 但是 他剛到
They were going through stuff, but-He's just arrived.
我回頭給你回電話
I'll call you back.
你是蘭姆
You're Lamb?
這麼晚了 我還慘遭質疑
This time of night, I'm plagued by doubts.
我叫艾瑪·弗萊特 接替達菲的人
I'm Emma Flyte. Duffy's replacement.
一看就比達菲強
Well, you're already an improvement.
我指的是你不是腦殘 也沒有昏迷不醒
On account of not being brain-dead and in a coma.
小道消息說是你手下人導致他昏迷的
The grapevine says it was one of yours put him in that coma.
小道消息說什麼的都有 但大多數不靠譜
Well, the grapevine says a lot of things, but it's mostly the wine talking.
達菲之前那位可厲害多了
The guy before Duffy was altogether classier.
壞人山姆·查普曼
Bad Sam Chapman.
只是個綽號而已
That was just a name.
沒那麼壞
Wasn't that bad.
除了弄丟兩億五千萬英鎊這一點
Except for that bit about losing a quarter of a billion pounds.
我說他還不壞
Well, I said he wasn't bad.
沒說他完美無缺
Didn't say he was perfect.
帶我看看犯罪現場吧
Want to show me the damage?
你認識卡特懷特先生
You know Mr. Cartwright?
我有不在場證明 我當時在和戴女士蒸桑拿
I have an alibi, I was in a sauna with Lady Di.
你可以問她
You can ask her.
你認識卡特懷特先生
Do you know Mr. Cartwright?
哪個 隨便 兩個
Which one? Either. Both.
年輕那個是我的手下
Well, the younger one works for me.
爺爺曾給過我一份工作
The grandfather gave me a job once.
鞋不錯啊
They're nice shoes.
你有服裝補貼
You get a clothing allowance?
該死
Fucking hell.
準備好了
You ready?
所以你是那些棄子的負責人
So, you're in charge of the rejects.
他們不喜歡被稱為棄子
They don't like being called that.
那你怎麼叫他們 棄子
What do you call them? The rejects.
這裏 親愛的 看 你漏掉了一點
Here, love, look. You missed a bit.
裏面慘不忍睹
It's bad in there.
我見過慘的
I've seen bad before.
有人在21點03分按下了應急按鈕
Someone pressed the panic button at 2103.
本地警察21點49分抵達
Local police arrived 2149.
出警可真快 還好不是緊急情況
It's a good job it wasn't an emergency.
老人家上周按下過兩次按鈕
The old man pressed the button twice the week before.
一次是因為他忘了按鈕的用途 想按下去看看
Once because he'd forgotten what it was for and wanted to find out.
應急按鈕是可追蹤的 有人提到嗎
Those panic buttons are traceable, anyone mention that?
謝了 我會寫個註釋
Thanks. I'll make a note.
但我已經追蹤到他這個了 在廚房餐桌上
But I've already traced his particular button to the kitchen table.
你看了按鈕下面嗎
Did you look underneath it?
你在找什麼
What are you looking for?
我可舒適泡騰片
Alka-Seltzer.
我平常不喝酒 但我晚餐前喝了雪利酒
Not normally a drinker, but I had a sherry before dinner.
這是犯罪現場 不是藥房
This is a crime scene, not a chemist's.
他中了兩槍 一槍胸口 一槍正臉
He was shot twice. Once in the chest, once in the face.
似乎有些過分
Seems excessive.
雖然他有時挺煩人的 這我承認
Though he could be annoying, I'll give you that.
你似乎不太關心啊
You don't seem too concerned.
我之前也損失過特工 你以前是一線特工
I've lost joes before. You were an active.
對 那時你還穿紙尿褲呢
Yeah, when you were still in mittens.
他當時身上帶著這個
He was carrying this.
手機和錢包 都是卡特懷特的
Phone and wallet? Both Cartwright's.
那你找我幹什麼
What the fuck do you need me for then?
正式確認身份
Formal identification.
這可有點難
It's a bit of a challenge.
他身上有特別的記號嗎
Well, did he have any identifying marks?
他本來是有臉的 有用嗎
He used to have a face. That any help?
文身 傷疤 穿孔飾品 我怎麼知道
Tattoos, scars, piercings? Now, how the fuck would I know?
我要求他們上班時得穿衣服
I make 'em wear clothes around the office.
是他嗎
Is it him?
對 是他
Yeah, it's him.
你確定
You're sure?
是瑞弗·卡特懷特
It's River Cartwright.
那他在哪 誰在哪
So, where is he then? Where's who?
那個老不死的
The old bastard.
我們以前就這麼叫他
That's what we used to call him.
他真的是個混蛋 我可以保證
And he was a bastard. I can guarantee that.
我們不知道
We have no idea.
我猜你想低調處理此事 畢竟韋斯特艾克斯剛出事
I imagine you wanna keep this quiet, what with Westacres.
韋斯特艾克斯和此事有什麼關係
What does Westacres have to do with this?
沒什麼
Nothing.
但炸彈在倫敦爆炸 這是情報處掉鏈子
But a bomb goes off in London, it's an Intelligence Service fuckup,
很諷刺 恰好我們這位 小卡特懷特也是個廢物
which ironically describes our young Cartwright.
如果此事公開 網上那些鍵盤俠一定會誤會
When this gets out, the keyboard nutters will be joining the wrong dots.
公開前我們就能調查完畢
We'll wrap it up before it comes to that.
接下來的聲音是我在表達自信
Well, the next sound you hear will be me expressing confidence.
厲害了
Impressive.
你能想放就放
Can you do that to order?
怎麼 想再聽一聲
Why? Do you want another?
你真是既噁心又失禮
You are gross and inappropriate.
我正傷心難過呢 表達方式欠妥罷了
I'm working through my grief. It comes out in off ways.
你知道老卡特懷特可能去哪了嗎
Any idea where Cartwright senior might go?
不知道 我回去繼續睡覺了
No. I'm going back to bed.
你不考慮洗個澡嗎
Would you also consider a shower?
好啊 這個提議很誘人
Yeah, it's a tempting offer,
但我覺得現在不合適
but I don't think that's appropriate right now.
畢竟拋開其他事不談 我的一位隊員剛剛死掉
I mean, apart from anything else, one of my team just died.
(內附罰款通知單 警告)
(局長 克勞德·惠蘭)
進來
Come in.
看到溫特斯駕車闖入
...shows that Winters drove into the venue--
克勞德 我有 戴安娜 太感謝你了
Claude, I've got s-Diana, thank you so much for this.
這是我第一次參加 政府危機應對委員會會議
It'll be my first COBRA meeting, so I was wondering
所以我想問 你能不能跟我說說會議大致內容
if you might be able to give me a rundown of what to expect?
好 可以 我 拜託了 如果你不介意的話
Okay. Yep. Well, I'm-Please, if you wouldn't mind.
我最近很忙 所以 對 是的
I've got a lot going on, so... Right. Yes.
我就只挑重點說了 可以嗎
...I'll just stick to the headlines, if that's all right.
當然 有勞了
Sure, if you wouldn't mind.
要言簡意賅 言簡意賅
Keep it short but dense. Short, dense.
強調人工情報的缺陷
Stress the frailty of HUMINT.
別怕說不知道
Don't be afraid to say you don't know,
別說任何無法反覆驗證的東西
don't say anything that can't be triple-sourced,
別告訴他們任何你不希望洩露的事
and don't tell them anything you don't want leaked.
好 一定 你可以無視國防部部長
Yes, of course. You can ignore the Defense Secretary,
他只會想方設法削弱你 以提升軍方情報處的地位
he'll only want to undermine you to boost the standing of military intelligence.
我還必須警告你 如果首相反對你的任何提議
And I have to warn you, if the PM objects to anything you suggest,
內政大臣就會落井下石
the Home Secretary will put the boot in,
即使她剛剛贊同了你所有的話
even though she's agreed to everything you have just said,
但 你會沒事的 好 謝謝
but-I mean, you'll be fine. Yeah, but thanks--
但我是來通知你 又有一個人死了
But I came to tell you that there's been another death.
什麼 又有炸彈襲擊
What, another bomb?
不
No, no.
是槍擊案 和炸彈襲擊事件無關
A shooting. Unrelated.
但受害人是一名特工 不
But the victim is an agent. Oh, no.
瑞弗·卡特懷特 被他爺爺大衛·卡特懷特擊斃
River Cartwright, shot by his grandfather, David Cartwright.
大衛·卡特懷特
David Cartwright?
但他不是我們最厲害的特工嗎
But he was supposed to be one of our finest, wasn't he?
我是從沒見過他啦 但是
I mean, I never met him, but--
不好意思 他為什麼要槍殺親孫子
I'm sorry, why on earth did he shoot his grandson?
顯然他誤把他當成闖入者了 但弗萊特控制了調查
Apparently he mistook him for an intruder, but Flyte's got it locked down.
好 對了 你覺得她怎麼樣
Right. How's she working out for you?
很好 是了 我知道她不是你選的
Good. Yes. I know she wasn't your choice.
她是我選的
She was my choice.
只不過她選的條件是你的
It was the terms of her choosing that were yours.
我覺得你會看到 招個外人有什麼好處的 戴安娜
Well, I think you'll see the benefits of bringing in an outsider, Diana.
她不受任何內部政治的影響
I mean, she's unswayed by any internal politics,
這些都有助於她的可信度
all helps with the accountability drive, you know?
不要把卡特懷特的事公開
Let's not share this Cartwright incident with the public.
在找到大衛前不要 我們知道發生了什麼
Not until we've found David and we know what the hell happened.
好的 沒錯 我能明白其中道理 真是悲劇 戴安娜
Yeah. No, I can see the sense in that. Tragic. Diana?
是
Yep.
我在想 你會不會
Was just wondering-Just wondering whether you might
希望替我去參加 這個政府危機應對委員會會議
prefer to attend this COBRA meeting rather than me?
這是局長的職責
That's a First Desk duty.
大家都說 你在接替蒂爾尼期間
But by all accounts, you did such a sterling job
做得非常出色
filling in after Tearney.
鑒於目前的嚴峻形勢 再加上你顯然經驗豐富
Given the gravity of the situation and obviously your experience,
我認為也許你去出席 他們會自在得多
I think they'd be a lot more comfortable, you know, with you being present
回頭你再向我匯報 好嗎
and reporting back to me. Yes?
當然
Absolutely.
是嗎 你答應了 這 太好了 是的 你說什麼都行
Yes? Is that okay? Is it o-Great. Yes. Yep. Anything you say.
非常感謝 謝謝
Thank you so much. Thank you.
好了
Right.
你為什麼炸韋斯特艾克斯
Why did you bomb Westacres?
你的組織裏有多少人
How many are in your network?
下一個目標是什麼
What is the next target?
嘿
Hey.
下一個目標是什麼
What is the next target?
這就是讓嫌疑人招供的方法 讓我去審問即可
That's how you get a suspect to talk. Just put me in a room with them.
如果真有事瞞著你 我可以堅持更久的
I could've held out longer if I was actually holding something from you.
不 所有人都有扛不住的時候 我堅持了多久
No, everyone's got a breaking point. What was mine?
七秒 就七秒
Seven seconds. Is that all?
好了 給錢 見鬼
Right. Pay up. Fuck's sake.
真好 200個
Lovely. 200.
行 好
Yeah, all right.
現在我知道是什麼體驗了 我覺得我能堅持一分鐘
Now I know what it's like, I reckon I could do a full minute.
是啊 真的
Yeah. Yeah.
這裏到底怎麼了 漏水了嗎
What on earth's been going on here? Do we have a leak?
沒有 他給我用水刑來著
No. He's been waterboarding me.
為什麼
Why?
打賭 曲別針
For a bet. Paper clips.
曲別針是他的戒賭「鎮靜劑」
Paper clips are his gambling methadone.
這個辦公室已經夠亂的了
This office is in enough of a state already.
一定要把頭髮擦乾 親愛的
Do dry your hair, dear.
當年在總部
You know, back at the Park,
我是「數據庫女王」的辦公桌分配員之一
I was one of the Desk Allocators to the Queens of the Database.
你說過了
You have mentioned it.
我依然不知道那是什麼意思
Still not sure what it means.
意思就是我坐在所有部門主管的對面
It means that I was across the management of every office.
我知道誰什麼時候在做什麼
I knew who was doing what, when.
我覺得管理這地方更具挑戰
And I find running this place more of a challenge.
你們打算什麼時候把聖誕裝飾收起來
When are you going to pack up the Christmas decorations?
我們拋硬幣決定了 雪莉會收
We flipped for it. Shirley's gonna do it.
才不是 三局兩勝
No, I'm not. Best of three.
趁還沒給我們惹上霉運 快把飾品收好
Well, just pack them up before you bring us bad luck.
我們的運氣已經不能更霉了
Our luck can't get any worse.
該死
Blast.
我把這些上周的文件退給你們
I'm giving you these back from last week.
怎麼 是議會收到的噪音投訴清單
What, the list of noise complaints to councils?
這些需要按日期排序 是
They need to be in date order. Right.
好吧 凱瑟琳要求 這種文件按投訴數量分類 所以
Right, well, Catherine wanted things like this grouped by number of complaints, so...
凱瑟琳不在這裏 對嗎
Catherine's not here, is she?
隨便啦
Whatever.
我們怎麼做都沒意義
Pointless however we do it.
早上好 JK 小心腳下
Morning, JK. Do watch your footing.
還是你喜歡被稱為科
Would you prefer Coe?
科先生
Mr. Coe?
他說過話嗎 一個字也沒說過
Has he said anything yet? Not a word.
說實話 我對他這個狀態感到很開心
Which, to be honest with you, I'm pretty happy about.
他常常做這個動作
He just does this?
在工作間隙就做 對 所以請趕快給他點活幹吧
In between work, yeah, so please give him some work quick.
1.95鎊
1.95.
(惡魔的心態)
什麼人會炸滿是顧客的購物中心啊
What kind of person blows up a shopping center full of people?
讓人不禁去想下一個目標是什麼
Makes you wonder what's next.
是 下一個是佳發蛋糕
Yes. Jaffa Cakes. That's what's next.
再來點我可舒適
And some Alka-Seltzer.
給 謝謝
There you go. Cheers.
你們摧毀了我
You have crushed me.
對我施暴
Wreaked violence upon me.
只有現在我才能得到自由
Only now will I be free.
兩分鐘後抵達
Two minutes out.
我被你們的系統囚禁多年 你們將為此付出代價
You will suffer for the years I spent imprisoned by your system.
上帝自有安排 我不會是最後一個
God willing, I will not be the last.
你們很快會從我兄弟們那裏聽到消息 怎麼樣
You will hear from my brothers soon. Well?
蘭姆確認了屍體就是瑞弗·卡特懷特
Lamb identified the body as River Cartwright.
那就確定了
That's confirmed, then?
蘭姆給你惹麻煩了嗎
Lamb give you any trouble?
我之前對付過蘭姆這樣的男人
I've dealt with men like Lamb before.
我覺得你沒有
I don't think you have.
大衛在哪 依然下落不明
Where's David? Still missing.
一位鄰居聽到半夜時有汽車駛離
A neighbor heard a car drive off in the middle of the night.
可惡的卡特懷特一家
Those bloody Cartwrights.
他們為什麼 非要在我們忙不過來時搞這些
Why do they have to do this when we're stretched so thin?
找到老卡特懷特
Find Cartwright senior.
我不是該調查韋斯特艾克斯案
Shouldn't I be on Westacres?
我聽說你們追蹤到了 炸彈襲擊者所在的公寓
I heard you traced the bomber back to a flat.
此刻正有一支武裝小隊突襲那裏
There's an armed unit going in right now.
我要你去查卡特懷特謀殺案
I want you on the Cartwright murder.
兩分鐘後抵達 長官 有人進出公寓嗎
Two minutes out, ma'am. Has anyone been in or out of the flat?
我們開始監視後還沒有
Not since we've had eyes on it.
長官 這是溫特斯 昨天下午1點剛過時出門的畫面
Ma'am, this is Winters setting out just after 1:00 p.m. yesterday.
我們從今天凌晨4點就開始監視了 無人機也已升空
We've been on it since 4:00 a.m. today. Our drones are up.
窗簾都拉上了 所以我們無法確定
Curtains are drawn, so we can't be certain,
但據我們所知 那裏沒有其他人
but as far as we know, there's no one else in there.
這不代表裏面沒人 也許有共犯
Doesn't mean there isn't. Might be accomplices.
把那些小孩撤離
Move those children.
好 把那些小孩撤離
Okay. Move those children.
嗨 抱歉 我遲到了
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
後面有動靜嗎
Any activity at the back?
還是沒有 長官
Still nothing, ma'am.
行動
Proceed.
警察 阿爾法1隊進入大樓
Police! Alpha-1 entering the premises.
開門了 警察
Opening! Police!
安全
Clear.
安全 安全
Clear. Clear.
安全
Clear.
安全 安全
Clear! Clear!
安全
Clear.
他活得像個和尚
He lived like a monk.
公寓安全 長官
The flat's clear, ma'am.
這裏沒什麼東西
There's not much to go on here.
讓鑒證科的人過去 我要把那公寓翻個底朝天
Get forensics in there. I want every inch of that flat turned over.
明白
Understood.
好 兄弟們 讓白大褂來搞科學調查吧
Right, boys, let's let the white coats in here to do their science.
長官
Sir.
找到一本護照
I found a passport.
和他用來租車的身份一致
It's the same ID he used to hire the car.
(羅伯特邁克爾溫特斯 英國公民)
他沒有隱藏身份
He wasn't hiding himself.
因為他知道自己要死了
Because he knew he was gonna die.
科學專家來了
Here come the boffins.
希望你們這些野蠻人沒有把這裏搞亂
Hope you animals haven't trashed the place.
沒什麼可搞亂的
Nothing to trash.
徹查整個公寓 有些多餘的衣物 靴子 一個睡袋
Swept the whole flat, some spare clothes, boots, sleeping bag.
大概就這些 對
That's about it, yeah.
走吧 滾蛋
Go on then. Fuck off.
給這裏來點光線吧
Let's shed some light on this place.
該死
Shit.
出什麼事了
What just happened?
我 快回答
I-Come on.
好像有炸彈陷阱 長官 老天 什麼
I think there was a booby trap, ma'am. Jesus Christ. What?
長官 三人死亡 見鬼
Ma'am, three dead... Oh, fuck.
可能有更多人受傷
...possibly more injured.
把人撤出來 封鎖區域
Get them out. Lock it down.
疏散整個街區 派一個新小隊去
Evacuate the entire block, and get a new team in.
我們必須弄清有沒有第二個放炸彈的人
We need to know if there's a second bomber.
是 長官
Yes, ma'am.
見鬼 這真是一場災難
Oh, fuck. This is a disaster.
徹頭徹尾的災難
Absolute bloody disaster.
克勞德
Claude.
Claude?
抱歉 我從沒見過這種事
I'm sorry. I've just never seen anything quite like this
發生在我眼前 我 是 但你必須承擔責任
in front of my own eyes before, so I-Yeah, but you need to shoulder it.
對 你說得對
Yeah, you're right.
我最好再向首相匯報一下 發表一份聲明
I suppose I better update the PM again and issue a statement.
不 你必須先通知家屬
No. You have to tell the families first.
他們不能從新聞上得知此事
They can't find out about this on the news.
當然
Of course.
我不知道自己剛才 謝謝你 戴安娜 你太可靠了
I don't know what I was-Thank you, Diana. You're a real rock.
情況更新
Where's my update?
正在疏散樓裏的人 長官
Evacuating the building now, ma'am.
真是一團糟
What a mess.
羅迪裏克 在
Roderick? Yeah?
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
拿走卡特懷特的電腦
Taking Cartwright's computer.
為什麼
Why?
因為他死了
Because he's dead.
什麼 怎麼了
What? What's going on?
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?
羅迪說瑞弗死了
Roddy just said that River's dead.
這玩笑不好笑 何
Sick joke, Ho.
不是玩笑 是事實
It's not a joke. It's a fact.
你怎麼知道的 蘭姆告訴我的
How would you know? Lamb told me.
蘭姆告訴你什麼
Lamb told you what?
這裏是什麼情況
What's going on in here?
卡特懷特死了
Cartwright's dead.
什麼叫他死了 哈哈 很好笑
What do you mean he's dead? Very funny.
蘭姆告訴我說卡特懷特死了
Lamb told me Cartwright's dead.
「我會晚點進辦公室
"Will be late in.
昨晚通宵鑒定卡特懷特的屍體」
Up all night identifying Cartwright's body."
一定是玩笑 拜託 什麼 在哪 怎麼回事
It's got to be a windup. Come on. What? Where? What?
他一定在笑呢
He must be having a laugh.
這根本說不通啊 你跟蘭姆說過話嗎
This doesn't make any sense. Have you spoken to Lamb?
沒有 所以
No. So--
什 你認為他死了 但你要偷他的電腦
Wha-So you think he's dead, but you nick his computer?
這不叫偷他的電腦 他死了
I'm not nicking his computer. He's dead.
任務日誌上說大衛·卡特懷特家有槍擊報告
Duty log says shots reported at David Cartwright's.
發現屍體
Body found.
我的天
Oh, my God.
該死 這都怪我
Oh, shit. This is my fault.
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊 我叫他去的 去哪
Oh, my God. I told him to go. Go where?
我叫他去看看爺爺 他爺爺開槍把他打死了
I told him to go and see his grandfather, and his grandfather fucking shot him.
見鬼 這不是真的 什麼
Fuck. Tell me this isn't true. What?
竟然又發生了
Tell me this is not happening again.
不 怎麼又出這種事啊 我們甚至還不瞭解情況
No, this is not happening again. We don't even know the circumstances.
我們知道他死了 不是嗎
We know he's dead, don't we?
我們還需要瞭解什麼 他死了
What else do we need to know? He's dead.
說個好消息吧 我有女朋友了
Well, in happier news, I have a girlfriend.
你這個王八蛋
You're a fucking prick!
路易莎
Loui-Louisa!
好痛
Fuck!
心平氣和地接受現實吧 你錯過機會了
Make your peace. You missed your chance.
倫敦反恐警察和安全部門確認
Counterterrorism police and the security service
他們在追查
in London have confirmed they are following
馬修阿姆羅利瓦拉 繼續調查
all potential leads as the investigation into the bombing
韋斯特艾克斯購物中心爆炸案
of the Westacres Shopping Center continues.
然而一位發言人證實 他們不知道羅伯特·溫特斯
Whilst a spokesperson confirmed they don't know how Robert Winters
是如何獲取他所使用的裝置所需原料的
acquired the ingredients for the device he used,
據瞭解 居民們
it's understood that residents...
一直在配合警方詢問
...have been assisting police with their inquiries.
同時 25歲的傑克·沃頓
Meanwhile 25-year-old Jack Wharton
是最新公佈姓名的襲擊受害者
is the latest victim killed in the attack to be named.
據報道 他的兄弟在爆炸中受傷
His brother was reportedly injured by the blast.
至此 全部23名爆炸案遇難者的身份
This means that all the 23 people who died
都已經確定
in the bombing have now been identified.
今早 武裝警察巡邏幾條主要
This morning, armed police patrolled several major...
傑克遜 你想怎樣
Jackson, what do you want?
這個歡迎很熱烈啊 你可以加點感情進去的
That's a nice welcome. You could have put some feeling into it.
我加了 只不過不是你想要的那種
I did, just not the kind you were hoping for.
打算邀請我進來嗎 不打算
Gonna invite me in? No.
那我強行進來呢
Mind if I come in anyway?
我帶了早餐來
I brought breakfast.
我吃過了 而且那不叫早餐
I've already eaten, and that's not a breakfast.
那喝一杯如何
How about a drink then?
就算對你來說 現在喝也早了點
Bit early, even for you.
我是說喝一杯水
I meant a glass of water.
你來幹嗎
So, why are you here?
就不能來看看老朋友
Can't drop in on an old friend?
不太可能 這麼說也不對
Unlikely and inaccurate.
我剛剛鑒定完瑞弗·卡特懷特的屍體
I've just come from identifying River Cartwright's body.
我想第一個告訴你
I wanted you to be the first to know.
看吧 瞧 早餐 裏面有橙子呢
There, you see? Look, breakfast. Got orange in it.
水果 有益健康 瑞弗 怎麼會
Fruit. Healthy. River? How?
胸口和臉部中槍
Bullet to the chest and a bullet to the face.
整個討人厭的表情都沒了
Literally wiped the annoying look off it.
你聽了都沒反應嗎 這就是我的反應
Aren't you going to respond? This is me responding.
在哪發生的
Where did it happen?
洗手間裏
In the bathroom.
跟當年一樣 是吧
Just like old times, eh?
你打算告訴其他人嗎
And will you tell the others?
我給何發了條短信
Well, I sent a text to Ho.
我想他現在應該已經告訴大家了
I expect he'd have spread the word around by now.
你發了條短信
You sent a text?
我可沒打算發推文
Well, I wasn't gonna tweet it.
老天 斯坦迪什 人命關天啊
Jesus Christ, Standish, a man died.
你知道這消息 會給路易莎帶來多大打擊嗎
You know what this news will do to Louisa?
所以我才發給何 我很講究策略的
That's why I sent it to Ho. I know how to be tactful.
那麼 既然你已經告訴我 這個壞消息了 你可以走了
So-Well, now that you've told me this terrible news, y-feel free to leave.
能看出來 你很忙
I can see you're busy.
你就不問問是誰的洗手間嗎 誰的
Aren't you gonna ask whose bathroom? Whose bathroom?
抱歉 只能告訴需要知道的人
Sorry, need-to-know.
你很開心吧
You're enjoying this.
能喝杯水就更開心了
Well, I'd enjoy it more with a glass of water.
你知道通宵不睡的人有多缺水
You know how dehydrated you get after an all-nighter.
老天
For God's sake.
你一個人住
Are you alone?
對 我該先問問的
Yeah, I should have asked.
我看起來像有伴的樣子
Do I look like I have company?
好吧 我必須問的
Yeah. Well, I had to ask, you know.
有些污名可不好洗刷 你應該知道
It's hard to shake off a reputation. Well, you should know.
你認識的每一個人都認為你是個大混蛋
I mean, everyone you've ever met has pegged you as an utter bastard.
但我不用受你氣了 因為我辭職了 記得嗎
But I don't have to put up with you anymore because I quit. Remember?
至少我嘗試辭職了 我給人事部寫了三封同樣的信
Well, I tried to. I've written the same letter to HR three times.
是 我知道 他們總把信轉發給我
Yeah, I know. They keep forwarding it to me.
文件總得有人批嘛
Something about ratifying the paperwork.
老天 蘭姆 問題到底出在哪
For God's sake, Lamb. What's the problem?
你多年來一直刺激我 然後我終於做了讓你如願以償的事
I mean, you spent years goading me, and then I finally did what you wanted.
在該死的辭職信上簽字啊 讓我繼續過我的人生
Just sign the damn papers, and let me get on with my life.
我想確保你瞭解自己的心意
I wanna make sure you know your own mind.
對 想像一下
Right, imagine how I'd feel
如果你後悔不已 酒癮復發 我該有多難受
if you wound up full of regret and had a relapse.
我可不想背負這種良心債
I wouldn't want that on my conscience,
你會整天以淚洗面 借酒消愁
you getting all weepy and hitting the bottle.
人們說酒鬼都在找借口
Now, they say drunks are just looking for an excuse.
我不怪你 這是一種病
I'm not blaming you, it's a disease.
對了 是他爺爺的
It was his grandfather's, by the way.
什麼
What?
他爺爺的洗手間 不是因為你問我才說的
His grandfather's bathroom, not that you asked.
你也沒問是誰
You also didn't ask who.
什麼誰 誰槍殺了瑞弗
Who what? Who shot River.
因為你和我一樣 知道他還活著
Because, like me, you know he's alive.
別耍花樣了
So stop playing games.
你剛剛告訴我說 你確認是他的屍體
You've just told me you'd identified his body.
是啊 你對當時的情況表現得非常不在意
Yeah, and you were remarkably incurious about the circumstances.
我驚呆了 好嗎
I'm in shock, okay.
你驚訝的是我來了 而不是
You're in shock at me being here, but you're not in shock
瑞弗還活著 因為你見過他
at the idea of River being alive because you've seen him.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
一派胡言 才不是
That's absolute rubbish. No, don't.
拜託 斯坦迪什 不
Please, Standish. No--
你很不擅長這一套
You're no good at this.
再說了
And besides...
他的車就停在外面
his car's outside.
是的 好吧 他來過
Yes. Okay. He was here,
但現在不在這裏了 好 這還差不多
but he's not here anymore. All right, that's better.
好了 請別裝了
Now, please don't pretend
你一定把那個老混蛋藏在臥室了
you haven't got the old bastard stashed away in the bedroom.
傑克遜 瑞弗叫我保護他
Jackson. River asked me to protect him.
滿意了
Happy now?
你是瞭解我的
You know me.
知道我什麼時候不是滿心歡喜
When am I not full of joie de fucking vivre.
很好 你現在就從我的臥室裏出去吧
Good. Well, perhaps you could leave my bedroom now.
嘿
Hey!
哥們
Mate.
瑞弗在哪
Where's River?
(巴黎德士)
你到底是誰
Who the hell are you?
還有多久到
How much longer?
沒多遠了
We aren't far now.
字幕翻譯 吳夢熊